[Music]
welcome back 60 points lower we are
at 15 666 at this point in time and
things are looking uh a little uh off
bhl has backed an order worth about 1
405 crores for
nuclear steam generators from npcil
uh that is information coming at the
bottom of your screen
the monthly life insurance data came out
yesterday and now we have
uh data for from the general insurance
space my colleague yash
jain is joining in and now we have a few
listed general insurance players as well
with details yeah show it to you so
prashanth traditionally as in
pre-covered levels
the general insurance sector was seeing
a growth of about 15 to 18 percent when
it comes to the premium collection
but seems like those levels have
remained untouched and continue to do so
as far as the data in the recent past is
concerned for the sector
in the month of june the premium has
grown by just about five percent on a
year on your basis
if you look at quarter one fy 22 growth
that has
shown some strength that has grown by 11
on a year-on-year basis
uh speaking about the two listed
companies for icici lombard
are not very impressive growth i would
say because in the month of june
the premium growth is almost flat on a
year-on-year basis
in the first quarter of fi 22 uh the
premium growth uh shows about 13 percent
as far as year-on-year comparison is
concerned new india is one company which
has seen strong growth in the month of
june as well as the first quarter so in
the month of june the premium is up
about eight and a half percent on a year
on your basis and for the first
quarter itself the growth is up 17 and a
half percent
on a year-on-year basis so clearly uh
the sector as well as individual
companies when compared on a
month-on-month basis the growth
has receded from those 15 levels and
seems like it will take some time for
these companies to get to that point yet
yes uh thank you very much uh for that
as
promised let's uh chat a bit about tcs
we will have uh
icsa security sudhir joining in he's
recently downgraded tcs post their
earnings but before that
let's just quickly tell our viewers how
the numbers look reported numbers as you
can see is below street expectation
so dollar revenue growth has come in at
2.8 percent constant currency revenue
growth and 2.4
but the miss as you can see is an
account of the india business which is
five percent of the overall revenues
it fell by about 14 and according to the
management it's much higher than what
you know they were earlier anticipating
so that explains the miss if you strip
that out as well as some
you know execution issues that they
faced in the asia pacific region
the core markets and verticals have done
very well for the company
margins have fallen on expected lines by
130 basis points due to the full quarter
impact of wage hike
and that is impacting their
profitability which is down two and a
half percent sequentially
that said uh the uh business indicators
long-term business indicators look
intact so one is the deal wins up 17
percent on a year-on-year basis
uh hiring has been at a record level for
the second consecutive quarter
but the concern is that attrition is
also picking up
and tcs is a company which has a you
know a robust
training program they were the ones who
have given two wage hikes in a span of
six months so even a company like tcs
has seen a nutrition increase of 140
basis points on a quarter on quarter
basis so that is a trend that we need to
monitor very closely
for the full year uh you know some of
the key takeaways are from the
management while they did reiterate
their double-digit guidance they are
watchful of the way the situation
emerges
and particularly on margins uh
discretionary spend has started coming
back
in fact the management expects most of
the discretionary spend to come back to
pre-corbit levels
by the end of fi 22 barring perhaps a
little bit on travel side so that is
going to be
you know a margin pressure that the
street will be uh you know closely
watching it in fact
uh listening to the management when we
had a chat with them earlier today
i believe that from the
time that you've spoken about our
conviction in it has only grown stronger
and we are seeing examples of that and
we shared that
with you in terms of multiple instances
where enterprise adoption is
accelerating you would like volume
growth with margins
we're moving into a space that typically
traditionally we have not participated
in
what it is allowing us to do is we are
ending up running the
what's called the integration management
office being a significant part of that
being part of their what's called the
day one planning
which is the post merger scenario and
laying out the roadmap of the sequence
in which this energy
value creation will happen
so these are areas that we were
traditionally not participating in
and traditionally they were seen as
consulting areas
but by leveraging our contextual
knowledge and proactively going forward
we are moving into these spaces
our discretionary spend which had uh
has started uh uh seeing an uptick
in cuban and we expect uh some of them
uh to go back to pre-pandemic levels uh
by the end of this year
uh while travel might take
a little more time to recover but
most of the spend would go back having
said that
we have also said that growth remains
our biggest lever
on margins and other factors
depending on how they play out in a
normal situation
we are very confident to maintain and
sustain margins
we were at 7.2 last last quarter 8.6
now uh you know this i said this earlier
also that this is an artificial number
during the
during the pandemic times uh we are you
know normally operating at 11 to 12
percent uh
attrition levels you know and and uh
even in at peak uh
you know hot job market situations we
also have seen
uh 13 to 14 levels also so this is
something which we which is part of our
operating model and and uh with our our
overall strategy for sourcing
uh uh significant uh you know source uh
is campus across the globe not just
india but in
north america in in apac in latam
everywhere
all right